Speaker 1: Arizona to hear what the two candidates running for office, this ever important office, want to do for this wonderful state. They changed the date on us and we cleared our schedule again for today. Unfortunately, I'm running against a coward who's afraid to stand on a debate stage and talk about what she wants to do for Arizona. And unfortunately, PBS and ASU have done a backroom deal with that coward to give her air time that she does not deserve.
Speaker 1: They have canceled this, they have canceled this, and it's absolutely wrong. I need to remind people that it is we, the taxpayers, who own PBS and who own ASU. This is not the DNC that owns this. And what's going on here is absolutely wrong. Now I know, let me assure you, if the tables were turned, and I had been cowardly, and I refused to debate, then we would not have the same thing happening today.
Speaker 1: they would have Katie Hobbs sitting there on stage alone. I was ready to sit down with Ted to talk about the issues facing Arizona, and unfortunately they had to cancel that because PBS has done the wrong thing once again, and they have capitulated to Katie Hobbs. This is outrageous, this is truly outrageous. They know that the reason that she's giving for not wanting to do this debate is not true. She said it would create a circus-like atmosphere.
Well,
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what, Katie Hobbs. You're the one that has created a circus-like atmosphere. You keep reminding the world that you're a coward and afraid to do a debate. She said I might yell at her. I would never yell at somebody. Only cowards would say something like that.
She
Speaker 1: said that I might say something inappropriate and embarrass the state of Arizona. I would never embarrass the state of Arizona. The question you should be asking Katie Hobbs is what was her excuse for not showing up for the Democrat primary debate? I've not heard anybody in the media ask her that. They're just letting her go with her bogus excuse of why she won't show up for a debate. Now PBS offered her a chance to come in on Tuesday and have a half an hour to herself.
Speaker 1: That is not right. She should not be given a half an hour of free air time. They've offered me now that same half an hour. I will agree to appear with Katie Hobbs next Tuesday on the stage together. And if she doesn't appear with me, they should kick her out and say she can't be on the airwaves at PBS. We the people own PBS. We the people own ASU.
Speaker 1: This is not an arm of the Democrat National Committee. And unfortunately, it appears that that's what it has become. Walter Cronkite would be rolling over in his grave right now at what's happening here. The people of Arizona deserve to hear
Speaker 2: from both people who are running for governor. This is a tradition.
Speaker 2: this is a tradition these debates have been going on for two decades now this is a tradition that
Speaker 1: katie hobbs is single-handedly destroying for the people of arizona and she needs to be called out for it asu needs to be called out for it pbs needs to be called out for it and frankly michael crow needs to be called out for it we are asking that everybody across this state contact the asu school of journalism call this number call k-a-e-t p-b-s
Speaker 1: and talk about why they are not holding a fair debate. Why they are capitulating to Katie Hobbs. And also call ASU President Michael Crow and ask why this would be allowed to happen. Why they are destroying the clean election debates that have been going on now for two decades. And they're allowing one cowardly candidate to destroy this entire debate system. Imagine next go around.
If
Speaker 1: the
Speaker 3: Democrats realize, "Wow, we don't have to sit on the debate stage with the Republicans anymore." If they don't have to sit on the debate stage with the Republicans, if they can just stomp their feet and demand a safe space, then they'll get their own time. Then PBS will capitulate and give them their own time. And we'll never have a debate system again. The people in the
Speaker 1: liberal
press,
I need
Speaker 1: to demand that your candidate, the one you guys are backing in the liberal press, show up and debate. The people of Arizona deserve this. I promise her, Katie, I promise you, you can write the questions for me. I promise you I won't yell, Katie. I promise you I won't interrupt you. And if you want to have an emotional support animal there as well, I will agree to that. But show up like a grown-up and
Speaker 2: debate.
We
Speaker 1: have serious issues facing this great state of ours. We've got the narco-terrorists controlling our border right now. How in the heck are you going to go up against them if you're afraid to debate me here at PBS? How in the heck are you going to go up against Gavin Newsom when he's stealing our water and fight back there, and when they're taking our energy?
how
Speaker 1: in the heck are you going to fight for companies to come to arizona when you have to go up against people like great governors like governor abbott and governor christy noem and governor ron desantis arizona
Speaker 4: will lose if katie hobbs is elected i think i know the real reason she doesn't want to appear and
i think
Speaker 4: you guys all know we sent it where are
Speaker 2: the checks guys these checks behind me
are an indicator of
Speaker 2: what katie hobbs has already cost this state
Speaker 2: It's going to be about three million dollars that you and I are paying for, the
Speaker 1: taxpayers of Arizona, because she's a twice convicted racist who paid women of color in her office $30,000 less than she paid white men doing the exact same job. These are checks that
Speaker 2: have already been paid out. More is to come.
Speaker 2: She's already cost us dearly. We found out this week that when she was in high school,
Speaker 1: that's where her racism began. When she started an outrageous slave auction at her high school, her yearbook shows this. We've
got a
Speaker 1: racist running against me, and you guys are running cover for her. She tried to bribe Talonia Adams out of not speaking to the press.
And
Speaker 1: that story didn't get any coverage by you guys. I never saw a headline on that. Let me tell you, if the roles were reversed
and I
Speaker 1: had this hideous of a background, you guys would be covering it nonstop. Shame on you for not covering Katie Hobbs the way she is. Katie Hobbs obviously hates people of color. Her past proves that. Why are you not covering that story? Why? I'm asking for the people of Arizona.
Speaker 1: She's against families being able to take their kids to a better school. This hurts our minority communities. Every student in this state deserves
Speaker 2: to have the best education. And with ESA for All, they will be able to get that. Katie Hobbs
Speaker 5: fought that.
She
Speaker 6: has a voting record that supported the rioters who burned down our cities and communities. Her voting record shows she opposed a border wall, she opposed a virtual border wall, she was opposed to asking the federal government
Speaker 2: to reimburse Arizona for the cost of our open border, and she's voted against the border strike task force. What is wrong with this woman? She's working against the people of Arizona. She wants to defund the police.
Speaker 2: She's voted to double our gas tax from $0.18 to $0.36. She put out a plan to help us with inflation that is a joke, and I noticed it got
Speaker 1: wall-to-wall coverage from you guys. She wants to lower taxes on a few items: diapers and feminine hygiene products. And that got a lot of coverage from
you.
We
Speaker 1: are planning to cut all of the food tax and cut all of the rent tax to help all Arizonans. We're going to be sending a half a billion dollars back into the pockets of hardworking Arizonans. I'm not sure that that got much coverage. But I think it's about time you start doing your job, covering who this woman is. She's a coward who has no chance to be a great
Speaker 2: governor in this state. And I don't think she's going to
win.
So
Speaker 2: if you have any questions about this, I'm hoping that you don't put the same headlines that I've seen already. We had nothing to do with this getting canceled. This was completely PBS. And it is outrageous that we're watching the decimation of a two decade tradition of debates that helped the voters decide who to vote for. And a coward
Speaker 1: named Katie Hobbs is behind it along with PBS. It's outrageous. Questions, anybody?
Speaker 7: Jordan. You recently saw an undercover journalism
Speaker 8: expose done by Project Veritas where Katie Hobbs ran from reporters again. She also, you know, she admitted to lying to an Uber driver, somebody that actually works for her, pays her taxes, and she wouldn't tell him what she does for a living or the fact that she's running for governor. What does that tell you about her confidence in her campaign and also her ethical standards?
Well, I
Speaker 9: don't know much. I haven't done a lot of research. I talked about the Project Veritas story that came out.
Speaker 2: All I saw was that she is running from a black reporter, which doesn't surprise me, spilling her food
Speaker 1: and drink all over and hiding in the bathroom. Surprises me not. This woman is a maniac. I'm shocked at the
Speaker 2: level of racism I've seen.
Speaker 2: You know, I can't tell you what's going on in her mind and why she lied to the Uber driver. It's interesting the Uber driver didn't
Speaker 1: even know who she is. I'm not shocked by that. She's been hiding in her basement. I
think if she
Speaker 1: walked through here, half the people wouldn't know who she is. She's been
Speaker 2: in hiding and she refuses to actually campaign across the state. Meantime, I'm campaigning across the state.
Speaker 2: I've cleared my schedule for a debate, I've cleared it again for another debate, and I'm willing to clear it again.
And
Speaker 1: I will be showing up next Tuesday, and PBS better put both of us on stage at the same time.
So, it is true that
Speaker 11: Arizona PBS does receive some public funding. Would you push the state legislator or
Speaker 12: the Board of Regents to divest funding from PBS if you were elected governor?
Speaker 2: Well, seeing as how they appear to be an arm
of the democracy
Speaker 2: Democrat Party, I think we need to look at it. This is not bipartisan, this is biased. This is absolutely biased. Katie Hobbs, in her refusal to appear on a debate stage with me, pretty much should have shut down her ability to even make it on the air at this station. But yet, they are so obviously in the tank for her that they're giving her an
Speaker 13: opportunity to appear on this stage, it's wrong. And we should look at that, we really
Speaker 14: should.
Speaker 14: Arizona
Speaker 15: Clean
Speaker 16: Elections, what was your conversations like with them, and will you participate in their future event, whatever that may be?
Speaker 2: I feel for Arizona Clean Elections. They've put this on for two decades now. It's been a wonderful opportunity. Before I ran, I used to watch the debates. It was a great way for me to find out what these candidates are all about.
Speaker 2: And honestly, I really, truly want to speak to
Speaker 1: Democrat voters out there. As all of you know, I was registered for Democrat for a short time. I was registered for four years, many years ago, as a Democrat. I ask that you ask yourself, why is it that Katie Hobbs will not debate? What is she trying to keep from you? What is she hiding? And I know that a
Speaker 2: lot of Democrats are starting to wonder if the Democrat Party that they signed up for years ago is still the same Democrat
Party.
Speaker 2: think it's pretty obvious it's not
Speaker 1: it's changed so much they don't care about the working-class anymore they've really become globalists they're pushing things like vax mandates on our children and on our working-class
Speaker 2: folks I really ask Democrats to take a close look at what's going on in the Democrat party because it's changed it's not the
Speaker 1: Democrat party you likely signed up for and I hope that the clean elections
Speaker 1: folks and the whole commission can survive this, but I really think Katie Hobbs is really going to be behind killing this entire tradition and it's unfortunate for the voters of this great state
of
Speaker 17: Arizona. What's your organization? Is that a real paper?
- It
Speaker 18: is, you
Speaker 17: should read more. - Is it a paper or is it
Speaker 18: online? - It's online, it's a newsletter, you're gonna love it. Look, two questions. One, you mentioned backroom deals and Michael Crow. What do you know about how this decision was made? And I'll give you a moment, but I wanna follow
Speaker 2: up. - You know, I don't know a lot about it other than we know that Katie Hobbs,
you know,
Speaker 2: didn't wanna do the debate because she was afraid.
And then
Speaker 2: they agreed that because it's the rules, and it's law, that they can't deny me the ability to do the debate.
Speaker 2: And so I was gonna have a half an hour on stage alone. Now I wanted Katie Hobbs to show up. I was hoping I would show up today and that she would be here. I asked the Clean Elections folks, even though I didn't have to, I said, "Please keep that deadline open until the moment it starts." Because if Katie Hobbs decides she wants to show up, I want her on that stage with me because I care about the people of Arizona and I think they deserve
Speaker 3: that. And then I find out late this afternoon
Speaker 2: that PBS did a go around
And
Speaker 2: they were offering Katie Hobbs a half an hour on PBS at a different
Speaker 1: time. And our team and our attorney contacted Clean Elections. They didn't know about it. Clean Elections apparently contacted PBS and found out that ASU may have been behind it. We're trying to figure out who made that decision because it's wrong. And I think all of you, I really do believe all of you agree that's wrong. You see how that is going to destroy these debates from here on
out.
If
Speaker 1: candidates don't have to appear with each other, they will opt to have their own half an hour. And it's dangerous, as you say, it's dangerous for
Speaker 19: democracy. Many of you say that. It's dangerous for democracy, so remember that.
- The
Speaker 21: follow-up here is-- - Anybody else, I've already got one for you.
up
Speaker 22: here i got two follow-ups it sounds like you're saying you don't have any evidence one question
Speaker 24: okay one one more uh it
Speaker 25: sounds like you're saying you don't have any evidence to back up that claim about backroom deals from michael probe
Speaker 2: but my question this was this this deal was made between between pbs and katie hopps and
Speaker 13: i've got some idea but i'm not privy to share it all with you do
we
Speaker 26: have a question anybody over here
Speaker 26: What's your name, what's your name and what channel
Speaker 27: are you with?
Katie Ops has
Speaker 28: given a lot of different reasons as to why she doesn't want to debate, she doesn't want it to be similar to the GOP primary, which she calls disjointed, she also says that Carrie Lake is an election denier. What do you say to someone who calls Carrie Lake an election denier?
Speaker 2: She's given a lot of reasons why she won't appear and none of them are true.
And
Speaker 2: I've heard nobody ask her, well, then what was your reason for not appearing against Marco
Speaker 1: Lopez, your Democrat challenger?
And I
Speaker 1: haven't heard that
Speaker 3: follow-up question from any of you with her. Do
you know
Speaker 3: what the answer is? Why did she not appear?
She was out talking
Speaker 3: with voters. You know what she is? She's a total BS-er. And if you guys are buying any of
Speaker 1: this, that means that you're not very smart. She's a BS-er.
She
Speaker 1: doesn't want to appear because she's afraid. She's coming up with every excuse in the book. And we all know it, guys. Let's face the facts. We all know these are excuses because she's afraid. Last week, she was on a stage separate from me, and she was given all
Speaker 3: softball questions. One of them was, "Name one thing that you've learned from the
Speaker 29: Latino community." She spent a minute and a half, could not think of one thing
that
Speaker 3: she's learned from the Latino community, which is a third of our state. That should have been front page news. Let me tell you, if that would have been me on a debate stage or a forum stage, I guarantee
Speaker 1: you that the Arizona Repugnant would have written five articles about it and a bunch of you would be still talking about it. I haven't seen any front
Speaker 3: page articles on that. She stuttered and stammered her way through a softball question of what has she learned from the Latino community.
She
Speaker 3: couldn't come up with one thing and I didn't see any of the mainstream news covering it
Speaker 1: You guys need to do some soul search in here. Are you political reporters or not? That's my question to you because the people deserve to hear this and they're not hearing it from you. Any
Speaker 30: other questions?
Speaker 31: you've already had
Speaker 32: to sir
you're
Speaker 33: gonna have to go
Speaker 32: what what are your policy sir to deal with this for the media I'm only answering one
Speaker 34: question I'm only
Speaker 35: answering one question I'm not answering
Speaker 36: questions from the repugnant
I'm not
Speaker 37: answering questions from the repugnant, but if you have a -- anybody else has one, I'm happy to answer.
Speaker 38: Quick and easy, Katie, PBS. PBS has offered you and Katie Hobbs 30 minutes separately. Will you accept their
Speaker 37: offer? Do you think that's fair?
Speaker 38: I'm asking you, will you accept the
Speaker 37: offer? You just asked, "PBS has offered us
Speaker 3: 30 minutes separate." And my question is, do you think that's fair? That means that Katie Hobbs, the coward,
Speaker 3: Not only has Juan, which I'm not letting her win this debate. I'm not going to let her call the rules for the debates. That's for the
Speaker 2: clean elections folks
to do.
Speaker 2: We're not going to let the coward decide how the debates go out. You either show up in debate or you don't. And so I will show up on Tuesday and I expect to be on a debate stage with her. I expect to be on a debate stage with her.
Speaker 13: Anybody else have
questions?
Last
Speaker 40 (higher-pitched voice): week, when Blake Masters had the chance to debate, he was asked about the 2020 election, and he said that he actually hasn't seen evidence of voter fraud, but that big tech and censorship tipped the scale for Joe Biden. Do
Speaker 41: you believe that there was evidence of voter fraud, or do you see it more the way that Blake Masters sees it?
-
Speaker 2: I've talked endlessly about this, and I find it funny. I'm happy to talk about the 2020 election, but when I do talk about it, you guys gripe that I talk about it. There were major problems in our election. I believe there was major corruption in our election, and I'm seeing it again in 2022. August 2nd, 2022, Katie Hobbs advising our counties on how many ballots to print,
Speaker 2: and one hour into the elections in Pinal County, they ran out of Republican-only ballots. We have major problems. We're gonna restore honesty in our elections when I'm governor. Next question,
Speaker 42: anybody? You with the beard
Speaker 43: in the back.
Who are
Speaker 44: you with?
Speaker 45: I never
Speaker 4: thought of it that way. I never thought of it that way. What I do know is she's a coward, and she's afraid that her racist past is going to come out, and she doesn't
Speaker 1: have a response to it. She doesn't have a response as to why she fired Telonia Adams when Telonia Adams asked or
Speaker 1: why am I making $30,000 less than the men in the office? She doesn't have a response. She said to, on the hot seat, basically, that she fired Telonia Adams for disobedience. What year are we in? This woman's a monster. She's afraid to answer the questions. Any other questions,
Speaker 6: Dennis? Dennis, channel
three. -
Speaker 47 (lower-pitched voice): Once again, you're criticizing the media. You've done that throughout your entire campaign. You've done that with me face to face.
Speaker 47 (lower-pitched voice): Any proposals on your part to deal with the media,
Speaker 48: any new laws to deal with the media?
Speaker 49: No, I'm not going
Speaker 3: to put a new law in. I just would hope that you guys would start acting like journalists and not propagandists and not acting like social justice warriors for the Democrat party. The people are on to it. Why are these headlines not being written correctly?
Katie
Speaker 3: Hobbs
Speaker 2: is destroying a tradition here through her cowardice. She's gonna destroy these debates from here on out. Mark my words, if you
Speaker 50: guys allow her to. If the headline reads what I've been reading, the headlines are reading which are
Speaker 51: inaccurate. Any other questions? Did you already have a question? Anybody
Speaker 52: else have a question? We've already
got one. A little
Speaker 52: louder, the bus is
going
Speaker 53: by.
Speaker 53: we might be on a slight recession do you think we'll go into a recession and what will you do i think
Speaker 2: we're already in a recession and that's why my tax plan we rolled it out and we want to help people as
Speaker 1: soon as possible we want to make sure that arizonans get relief we're going to send a half a billion dollars back to the people of arizona so that they can fight back on joe biden's outrageous inflation and complete incompetence and just a word of what to the to the
wise
Speaker 1: When we elect somebody like a Joe Biden, when we let somebody take office, like Joe Biden, who's incompetent, and somebody like Katie Hobbs, who's incompetent, this is the kind of stuff that happens. So vote wisely.
Speaker 54: Any other questions? You
Speaker 1: found
a lawsuit
Speaker 55: which was banned after the
Speaker 56: ballot in Arizona. Gochies County is considering a similar law.
Speaker 56: There's a proposal down there which election officials say would be pretty disastrous
to do that.
Speaker 56: Would you support what you're doing in Cochise County? And if you're governor, would you sign legislation to ban machine counting a ballot statewide?
We
Speaker 57: need to get rid of anything with software. Software can be hacked. We all know
Speaker 1: that. We probably all had our phones or our emails hacked or we've seen all kinds of things like that happen. We need to make sure our elections are secure.
And
Speaker 1: we know for a fact these electronic voting machines are not secure. They can be easily hacked. And there's only one thing I agree with Kamala Harris about, and it was the sound from her in 2017 when she said, these electronic voting machines, I witnessed them being hacked before my eyes. We can't have the vote counters counting with a machine that can be hacked. And I just want to make sure in every way that our elections are fair for Democrats, independents, and Republicans. I want every voter to know that their legal vote counts
Speaker 1: that it's counted properly and that on election night they go to bed knowing the winner
and they know
Speaker 1: that whether their guy won or lost, they can sleep soundly knowing the elections were fair and honest, and that's what we're going to deliver for the people
Speaker 54: of Arizona. Anybody who didn't get
a
Speaker 58: question? Sir. With a mask. Sir, with a mask. Where are you from? What station?
I'm
Speaker 60: where you used to work. Fox 10?
Speaker 61: Oh, my gosh. Fox 10
Speaker 60: showed up. What's your thoughts on the Tucson and Phoenix
Speaker 62: abortion decisions?
Speaker 62: And what's your stance on it?
- I
Speaker 3: can't, with a mask on, sir? I can't understand people who wear masks. Are you still wearing a mask?
Speaker 63: - What about
Speaker 64: the city of Phoenix, Tucson, and Phoenix abortion rulings?
- What are
Speaker 2: you referring to? Exactly what? I need more specifics than that. - They're not gonna enforce
it.
Do you
Speaker 6: think
Speaker 65: that the Territory Fair Law is put on hold right now? I can't
Speaker 6: decipher what your question is, get it a little more specific and then I'm happy to answer it. I've
Speaker 51: talked about this topic, that doesn't make sense to me. Anybody else have a question? The man in the right hand. The man in the back. The man in the back. Thank you.
Speaker 66: The Phoenix and Tucson.
I'm
Speaker 3: going to work with the lawmakers to make sure we have a system where voting is honest, where voting is honest. That's it.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what it's going to look like, but I want to know that every Arizonan goes to bed and knows that our voting system is honest. I've
Speaker 67: already answered my stance
Speaker 68: on... Sir? Sir?
You know
Speaker 52: what? Just because Fox 10 is finally showing up to cover me, I've answered it.
Speaker 69: I'm going
Speaker 3: to save as many lives as I can. We're going to follow the law, whatever the law may be. Right now, the law is up in the
Speaker 2: air. It looks like the 15-week ban is the law right now. I am running for chief executive.
That means I follow the law.
Speaker 2: follow the laws that are on the books and so that's the law i stand i'm personally pro-life i've answered the question just because fox 10 doesn't show up and cover me i can't help with that you haven't heard my answers
Speaker 72: any other
Speaker 43: journalists not get
Speaker 73: a question
Speaker 73: question about latino voters what have you learned about latino voters and are you
Speaker 74: worried at all about alienating latino voters with uh and they have been declaring the invasion we
Speaker 4: have so many latino voters
Speaker 1: uh coming over it's amazing and in our polling shows we're doing very well i i happen to live with three latino voters and i'm really proud of that my children are latino my husband's latino and i've learned a lot from latinos they are a third of our population they're the most hard-working
Speaker 1: devoted to their family, they show us that there's a balance in life. When you put your faith in God, you love your family, you work hard, you can.
You can
Speaker 1: have that American dream. And I learn a lot every day from my own family, my
Speaker 4: husband and children. They teach me something every day, and I consider them part of the Latino community.
Any other
Speaker 75: person not get a question? The blonde in the back. Hi,
Eliza
Speaker 76: Wall Street here. She used to be on Facebook.
Speaker 76: I don't think you
Speaker 2: all
Speaker 1: realize that the legislature writes our election law, right? Legislature. So whatever I want really doesn't matter. It's what the legislature comes up with, and then I work with them.
So
Speaker 1: we're going to work -- we want to make sure that we have secure elections, we have a voting system, and a vote counting system that is fair and can't be hacked, and can't be -- the software can't be hacked. We'll work together. We'll find some solutions. There was a lot of good legislation last go around that didn't get passed. What we want is for every Democrat, Republican, and independent voter
alike,
to
Speaker 1: know that our system is fair. We want to make sure that our voter rolls are cleaned up, that people who have moved are not on them, that people who have died are not on them. Real basic stuff. It's
Speaker 54: not brain science. It's not rocket science. It's real easy. Okay? Anybody else who didn't get a question? One
more question.
Speaker 2: Anybody who didn't get a question? Are you with an organization? What is it? Okay, yeah,
go
Speaker 77: ahead.
Speaker 77: We
Speaker 2: just heard from one of our sources that ASU had something to do with it and we're trying to figure out who made the choice to go around and make a backroom deal with the Katie Hobbs campaign to give her her own special carve out of a half an hour of airtime when she's denied
to
Speaker 2: show up for the debate. It's wrong, and I think all of you can understand. Hopefully I've explained why it's wrong. And again, what we want people to do, what we want people to do, is to make sure that they call ASU. We want people all around Arizona,
Speaker 2: Is to call ASU,
Speaker 1: call the School of Journalism, call PBS, call Michael Crow and explain to them that this is not the way you handle things. This is not the way you handle things. So if you could take a look at that, those are the numbers.
Speaker 54: Broadcast those and it would be great to put it out. Thank you so much. Appreciate it, guys.
- Backwards!